

DATA ENGINEER · DATA ANALYST

Moscow, Russia -> Ready to relocate

☑ oparanastasiya@gmail.com | 🛅 anastasia-oparysheva

Summary

Data engineer with professional experience 1+ year of DWH development. Analysis, refinement and refactoring of existing ETL/ELT processes. Development of new download streams on different layers of the DWH using Airflow. Work with different data sources such as Oracle, DBMS, Spark, HDFS. Passion about databases and enjoy customise development. Highly motivated to solve challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. Skills: SQL, Hadoop, DWH, ETL, Unix, Secure Shell (SSH), Spark, Airflow.

Work Experience _____

Sberbank

SENIOR DATA ENGINEER Aug.2021-ct

- Worked with systems inside sources and loading more than 100TB data at Data Lake in clusters based on Cloudera and developed incremental loading for 50GB for Data Cloud.
- Working on Data Quality Checking and use local instruments and custom queries. Created custom query of DQ that improve checking on 45%.
- Be proactive at improving at instrument ETL4Hadoop: wrote and structured documentation, create ideas that speed up developing for 40%.
- · Give instructions for junior developers in ETL4Hadoop technologies for better understanding in local Confluence.

Digital League

Data Quality Analyst

Mar.2021-Aug.2021

- Develop script on SQL to control Data Quality to prevent incidents on DWH.
- · Involved in process of incoming requests to repair incorrect data for the business and lead business conversation with the Customer.

Siblion

SIEBEL CRM DEVELOPER Oct.2018-Mar.2020

- Development of process B2B marketing, develop functional for client maintenance.
- Execution business processes using Open UI and standarts usability Siebel CRM.
- Create integration process using Workflow, EAI Data Transformation, EAI XML Convertor, Inbound/Outbound web-services.
- Develop screen form and existing functional in screen forms.
- Bug fixed from previously versions including Web-services.

Forward Telecom

PL/SQL Developer, Intern

Jul.2018- Aug. 2018

• Develop script on PL/SQL for education platform.

Education

Russian State University for the Humanities

Moscow, Russia

MASTER'S DEGREE, SOFTWARE AND COGNITIVE SUPPORT OF INTELLECTUAL ROBOTS AND PROGRAMMING OF INTELLECTUAL

Sep. 2018 - Jul. 2020

- SYSTEMS
- Science research in the Dorodnicyn Computing Centre. Lead in the development of intellectual robotics in simulation GAZEBO.
- Our plans include development an intellectual system like Shakey the robot from Stanford University. For one+ year we created a simulation of computer vision, manipulating of environment objects and mechanical movements.

Russian State University for the Humanities

Moscow, Russia

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, SOFTWARE AND COGNITIVE SUPPORT OF INTELLECTUAL ROBOTS AND PROGRAMMING OF INTELLECTUAL

SYSTEMS

Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2018

- · Had a science research at Institution of Russian Academy of Sciences Dorodnicyn Computing Centre of RAS for Graduation project.
- Had an active university life such as KVN, Debates club, English club and Chess club.